The adventure continues...
Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull is a
adventure, action film directed by Steven Spielberg.
Set during the Cold War, the Soviets—led by sword-wielding Irina Spalko—are in search of a
crystal skull which has supernatural powers related to a mystical Lost City of Gold.
Indy is coerced to head to Peru at the behest of a young man whose friend—and Indy's
colleague—Professor Oxley has been captured for his knowledge of the skull's whereabouts.
Indiana Jones, played by Harrison Ford.
Irina Spalko, played by Cate Blanchett.
Marion Ravenwood, played by Karen Allen.
Mutt Williams, played by Shia LaBeouf.
George 'Mac' McHale, played by Ray Winstone.
Professor Harold Oxley, played by John Hurt.
Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull is a 2008 American action
adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg, and written by David Koepp.
It is the fourth in the Indiana Jones film series.
Set in 1957, it pits Indiana Jones (Harrison Ford) against Soviet KGB agents led by Irina
Spalko (Cate Blanchett) searching for a telepathic crystal skull located in Peru.
Jones is aided by his former lover, Marion Ravenwood (Karen
Allen), and their son, Mutt Williams (Shia LaBeouf).
The supporting cast includes Ray Winstone, John Hurt, and Jim Broadbent.
Jeb Stuart, Jeffrey Boam, Frank Darabont, Lucas, and Nathanson wrote
drafts before Koepp's script satisfied the producers.
The filmmakers intended to pay tribute to the
science fiction B movies in the 1950s.
Shooting began on June 18, 2007, at various locations in New Mexico, New Haven, Connecticut,
Hawaii, and Fresno, California, as well as on sound stages in Los Angeles.
To maintain aesthetic continuity with the previous films, the crew relied on traditional stunt work instead of
computer-generated stunt doubles, and cinematographer Janusz Kamiński studied Douglas Slocombe's style from the previous films.
Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull had its premiere at the 61st Cannes Film Festival on
May 18, 2008, and was released in the United States on May 22, by Paramount Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, and was a financial success,
grossing $787 million and becoming the second-highest-grossing film of 2008.
A sequel, Indiana Jones and the Dial of Destiny, was released in 2023.
The film explores themes of treasure, mexico city, mexico,
saving the world, whip, leather jacket.